我早些时候曾谈到过世界人口增长带来的交通挑战。更多的人，
I talked earlier about the challenges of transportation as the world population grows. More people,
更多的汽车，更多的材料来支持那些需要从生产地出发的人
more cars, more material to support those people needing to go from where it’s produced
它被消费的地方。
to where it is consumed.
汽车是一项很棒的技术。他们彻底改变了我们的生活方式，但他们
Motorcars are a wonderful technology. They have revolutionized the way we live, but they
是非常危险的机器。每年有超过一百万人被汽车撞死
are very dangerous machines. Every year, over one million people are killed by motorcars
这个数字超过一百倍受伤。
and more than a hundred times that number are injured.
从全球来看，这每年耗费近五万亿美元。适合高收入人群
Globally, this is costing the planet nearly half a trillion dollars every year. For high-income
这些国家占其国民生产总值的近2％。在低收入或中等收入
countries, that’s nearly 2% of their gross national product. In low or middle-income
国家，这个数字较小，但它正在增长。这是一个发展成本
countries, that number is smaller, but it’s growing. And it is a cost of development is
通过交通伤害损失了大部分国民生产总值
that a larger proportion of your gross national product is being lost through traffic injuries
和死亡。如果我们看看2002年的10个主要死因，道路交通伤害
and fatalities. If we look at the 10 leading causes of death in 2002, road traffic injuries
排名第10。
were at number 10.
到2030年，它预计它们将增长到第八位。所以，虽然我们已经
By the year 2030, it’s predicted they will have grown to number eight. So while we’ve
为孕妇的健康做了很多事情并减少了结核病的发病率，
done great things for the health of pregnant women and reduced the incidence of tuberculosis,
道路交通伤害，汽车将在地球上杀死越来越多的人
the road traffic injuries, the car is going to kill more and more people on the planet
这是一件令人伤心的事情。
and that’s a sad thing.
以下是一些统计数据，按地区显示国民生产总值的百分比
Here is some more statistics, which show by region the percentage of gross national product
由于交通伤害和死亡而丢失。
that is lost due to traffic injuries and fatalities.
现在，汽车是由人类驱动的，人类是人类的主要原因
Now, motorcars are driven by human beings and human beings are the primary cause for
美国的机动车事故和1000万起事故的死亡人数
the motor-vehicle accidents and the fatalities of 10 million accidents in the United States
每年。这些事故中有一百五十万是由于司机的过错造成的。
each year. Nine and a half million of those accidents are due to the fault of the drivers.
我喜欢这里的引用。
I rather like the quote here.
有趣的是，大多数司机估计自己的能力。我特别喜欢这句话。
Interestingly, most drivers over estimate their own ability. I particularly like this quote.
这表明大多数美国学生，其中93％的人认为他们高于平均水平
It suggests that most American students, 93% of them believe that they are above average drivers
当然，这是不可能的。
and of course, that’s an impossibility.
底线是人类即使他们相信他们也不是很好的驱动因素
The bottom line is human beings are not very good drivers even if they believe that they
是。人类会导致事故，导致大量伤亡。
are. Human beings cause accidents which lead to a large number of injuries and deaths.
此图表显示了每万辆车的死亡人数
This graph here shows the number of fatalities per 10 thousand vehicles as a function of
时间和我们可以看到，在过去的50年里，一直在稳步改善
time and we can see that over the last 50 years, there’s been steady improvement in
减少每辆车的死亡人数，这是由于汽车设计的改进，
reducing the number of fatalities per car and it’s due to improvements in car design,
运动阻止人们在酒精的影响下驾驶，引进
campaigns to stop people driving under the influence of alcohol, the introduction of
安全带和安全气囊等。虽然总的改进很受欢迎，但是
seatbelts and airbags and so on. While the general improvement is quite welcome, the
可悲的是，有这个高原，改善的变化率确实下降了
sad thing is that there is this plateau, the rate of change of improvement has really fallen
我们被困在这个楼层。它不是零。这个数量有限
off and so we’re stuck on this floor. It’s not at zero. There is this finite number of
这些事故将发生在道路上车辆数量的一小部分。
accidents that’s going to happen as a fraction of the number of vehicles on the road.
人类驾驶员不完美的一个后果就是人驾车的方式
One consequence of the imperfection of human drivers is the way that the human-driven cars
彼此互动。该系统的动力学非常非常复杂并且已经研究过
interact with one another. The dynamics of this system is very, very complex and studied
由数学家和交通工程师。随着我们增加道路上汽车的密度，
by mathematicians and traffic engineers. As we increase the density of cars on the road,
流量实际上开始下降，这是我们亲身经历过的情况。
the flow rate actually starts to fall off and this is a situation that we’ve all experienced personally.
如果我从办公室窗户向外看，我看到一条繁忙的高速公路，这是一个景色
If I look out and down from my office window, I see a busy expressway and this is a view
当高速公路实际上非常拥挤并且没有特别快地移动时
of the expressway when it’s actually quite congested and not moving particularly quickly.
因此，在这种情况下的司机认为交通不流动，即
So the drivers in this situation are thinking that the traffic is not flowing, that the
道路被堵塞，但从我的鹰眼来看，我可以看到有很多道路
road is jammed up, but from my eagle eye view, I can see that there’s an awful lot of road
这是没有车的，这是人类司机的另一个问题，因为他们是
that’s got no cars on it and this is another problem with human drivers, because they’re
不太好，他们的反应时间非常慢，我们需要留下很大的差距
not very good, they’ve got quite slow reaction times really, we need to leave large gaps
在汽车之间。如果我们可以装载更多的汽车将会更有效率
in between the cars. It would be much more efficient if we could pack more cars into
所有这些空白的空间。反应时间很短的人意味着我们不能
all of that empty space. Human beings with a poor reaction times mean that we can’t
去做。如果我们这样做，我们就会发生更多事故。但也许，如果人类
do that. If we did that, we’ll just have tons more accidents. But perhaps, if human
如果我们有自动驾驶汽车或机器人汽车等，众生不会开车
beings weren’t driving the cars, if we have self-driving cars or robotic cars such as
这里描述的是一款谷歌自动驾驶汽车，那么事情可能会更好。
depicted here by one of the Google self-driving cars, then perhaps things could be better.
自动驾驶汽车正在采取一些平稳措施的情况如何？那
What would be the situation for autonomous cars that were doing some plateauing. That
我们是否有一组八辆汽车非常紧密地一起行驶并向下移动
is we have a groups of eight cars travelling very closely together and moving down the
道路，通过这种技术，我们将能够在路上安装更多的汽车。
road, with this sort of technology, we will be able to fit a lot more cars on the road.
他们旅行更顺利。他们旅行得更快。我们可以减少现有的汽车数量
They travel more smoothly. They travel more quickly. We could get more cars down existing
道路，而不必使它们更宽。
roads without having to make them any wider.